Our last presenter for this panel is
Yohanna Waliya with Vibe coding, AI,
digital text recycling
and the remediation of digital poetry.
Hello.
Good afternoon or good morning?
Yeah.
Please meet me to share my screen. Yes.
You do have permission, I believe.
Okay.
I don't know if you can see my screen
there.
Yes we can.
Okay.
As my topic
implies, vibe coding,
AI, digital text recycling,
and the limitation of digital poetry.
So my work is sent is to theorize the
AI aided.
Creative writing,
whereby we share co-authorship
with artificial intelligence
more especially in the in terms
of coding in the electronic literature.
We are
two in this paper.
We are we intended to show that section
that AI does the role that
AI plays in the production
in all because
coding all this
which natural language instruction
given to computer intelligence
in order to produce the work of art.
That's true prompting.
And in this kind of prompting
for electronic literature production,
we are interested
in in doing such kind of things.
We give computer the rhythm,
we give computer our affection
in order to produce digital poetry
and the system on its own.
Now, because it's trained on large
data sets,
it will speak to us
back, does give us feedback
according to what we want it to do,
and therefore we.
And finding ourselves
relating with non-human
that's pretending to be like human.
And in order to produce the work of art.
Then this kind of art,
because of a lot of data, said
that this computer is being fed upon.
We now have
a site, a
kind of recycling of text.
All we have in humanities most,
most often is the second of text.
But this last cycle of text bomb
fruit remediation
and what I call digital text is cycling.
Because as we know, we have our website.
Like there is this kind of objecting
that is used to happen
when we are initiating new
packages and models,
and then the previous ones
dies of like that.
And therefore that's what is making
some website that or what God oscillates,
it goes into obsolescence
because into like extension
because of the new programing languages
and also packages that are coming up
that are stronger than those
existing ones.
And what do we have
when we custom computer, what do we have?
We have three forces
that drive our composition.
We have the rhythm.
We have the intuition and our affection.
Then the
framework we use we we use three lessons.
That's three ways of approaching
computer production.
That's co-creation.
We have remediation.
We have text cycling.
We have consumer authorship.
Anyway. Remediation.
What we have we have new media
that fashion, old media, existing media.
The scaffolding of understanding AI
is the working of inherited digital text.
Then we have in the digital cycle
what do we do?
This is a new critical term
proposed by the paper.
I added poetically, processing and cooling
existing text back into circulation.
When you look at this,
we look at the cases of
where this AI has been used in the work
of Leonardo Florence,
where we has recycled,
the tiny protest and the
tiny protest protesters.
When you look at tiny protest
30 protests was on Twitter before,
but it went into extinction
because they stopped the bot
from running due to the change
of ownership of Twitter.
Then we have in the possible authorship
we no longer exist alone
before all humanity studies.
They are anthropocentric,
the center around human
being, the center around only human being.
But now, with advent
of another form of human beings
that have come to exist with us,
so that Zeno
and the artificial intelligence,
we have to redefine
who is the center of human
of our society today.
So we have to also accept that
that are also beings that are still with
us, that are non-human,
but they behave like human.
And that's why co-authorship in a,
in the present literary works has to do
with distribution across bodies, machine
and inherited material text.
Now, what is the role of AI
in our production?
The role AI serve as archive holding
the surface inherited digital text
style addresses the reuses,
then it works
as actively shaping our as koto.
It shepherds our languages alongside
the human poet in reality, in real time.
Then we have formative engine
driving the mutation and the
configuration of text into new poetic form
such as
the LMS, LMS and the rest.
The paper argue
that autoship is across human effect,
now affect now algorithm, interface
and inherited digital materials.
And this is what we have in our work.
So we have the work by.
Gauri by
Nick Ford and Tiny Protest by
Leonardo Flores
and Michael Work and Jamaica's.
What do we see here? The this the present.
The first one here has been are
has been, has been fucked
as it has been used
because the court is free
open access and everyone can use it.
But if the code was not prompted,
we didn't use human languages to do that.
But it is programed by somebody
and anybody can adapt to it
and use it for production.
I think from the last time I visited
the website, we have about 46 authors
who that have forked this work
and use it to produce
similar kind of generative literature.
30 protest has been imitated.
What you see 30 protest is one of the work
that
has has been remediated severally.
You can find it as well as an app
on a Twitter, though it has been stopped
now, it has been republished
on another platform differently.
So what do we see?
We see that there are set the text
and no more static
as the way we try to preserve
our society, our environment.
That's how our digital texts
have been preserved from extinction,
because most of the material of the text
that's the algorithm
material can also be obsolete.
So that's why also we do recycling and
and, and a limitation.
Then we have also my
I actually use AI like deep sick
and to recycle the text
and to make the work to be
similarly.
It's perfect because we have already
published it somewhere.
Then we have seen.
Also the implication goal here.
This is the Godhead that we have
as an example here.
So visual examples of those words
we have Jamaica's
which is an art is again.
And you see that one thing that I discover
is that the static values of this work
is imparted,
sympathetic in the sense that it is now
no longer human esthetics,
but also the machine and the human
has been collaborated together.
And that's what we call
what we call sympathetic esthetics.
And when you look at the tiny protest,
these are tiny protests
from one media to another.
When you see the last obligation
of standing protest
that is renamed as tiny Protest the King,
you discover that the esthetic value
there is more appreciated than the one,
the one that was published
on the top on Tepper.
Tepper
Tepper magazine, which is which we have
which had only the literature texts
where we call
mono poetic
kind of verses of one line or two lines.
They stick out. That's what we get there.
So this is tiny protest
work on the Twitter.
Now, continuous textual afterlife.
Why do we think about recycling,
as I mentioned earlier,
that because this text
can also go into extinction.
And the verb coding, let's put poems
circulate again, mutate
and remind across interfaces and
and how golden system
that stays finished.
So our text through our collaborative
will artificial intelligence.
We made this text to live forever to win
the world will change another technology.
So the AI preserves our work
and put it
bringing up all our work to life.
Our alter ship.
Is this a across human effect?
As I said earlier,
and now we have to look at what naming
the tools, questioning the implication
of those tools in our production.
The paper explicitly discloses
the AI tools
and platform involved in creative process.
Written disclosure itself
as a part of the poetic
is not a footnote to it.
That's why we have a static
what sensibility
do train models
bring into all impulse
on a human or on a form poems form?
That's what
we try to answer in this work now.
Cultural, we culturally,
whose language, imagery
and archives shape the database.
A poem draws on that.
The poem draws on mostly machine
cannot produce its own language is human
that imputed that language.
And it is our culture that is there.
Though through deep learning,
machine intelligence
can get new data sets learning from us.
And that's why we say
the machine is creative now,
because that's also how human
being creative human beings so work.
They read from large data set of different
books of literature, and then they now
follow the pattern of previous writers
to fabricate their own.
That's how also machine is being fed
or fed and fed with through artificial,
through machine learning and also deep
learning to now create its own work.
That's why we can boldly say
or convincingly say that the machine also
has its own culture now,
because the culture now is longer
human already, what we call it
now, artificial intelligence culture,
because they are able,
they they are able also to produce
learning from human
being to produce their own work.
Distinctive
poetics of electronic literature.
Vibe coding is situated
within the history of generative
and the procedural writing,
while making it turn towards affective
and intuitive code coding practice,
offering digital texture recycling
as a new perceptual term of understanding
a I made a digital poetry,
so that's why we have in our study
we have so many things
that we have bring them into light.
So we now look at,
our last word
is, as we have come to the end,
we have to conclude by saying that
AI recycle our texts,
and auto ship is being shared
between human and AI.
AI also can invent its own culture
from our own culture,
the same pattern that other human beings
and also produce.
And that is how
we see the work of electronic literature
moving from human to machine
and to sympathetic.
That is a sympathetic kind
of production, where human and machine
is sort of a techno
symbiotic producing culture
in the nearest future.
And from this time, first,
for what we begin to see is
that we share work
that are produced from human being
and machine as our own new culture.
Thank you for listening.